A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Activities, Series A FA338
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches by NAR, 1932-1966
  - Drafts and Reading Copies, 1932-1965
    - 1952 Jun-Oct (Box 125, Folder 1276)
    - 1952 Jun-Oct (Box 125, Folder 1277)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1278)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1279)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1280)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1281)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1282)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1283)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1284)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1285)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1286)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1287)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1288)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1289)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1290)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1291)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1292)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1293)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1294)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1295)
    - 1953 Nov-1954 Jun (Box 126, Folder 1296)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1297)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1298)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1299)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1300)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1301)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1302)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1303)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1304)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1305)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1306)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1307)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1308)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1309)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1310)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1311)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1312)
    - 1954 Sep-Oct (Box 127, Folder 1313)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1314)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1315)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1316)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1317)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1318)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1319)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1320)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1321)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1322)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1323)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1324)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1325)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1326)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1327)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1328)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1329)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1330)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1331)
    - 1954 Oct-1955 Dec (Box 128, Folder 1332)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1333)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1334)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1335)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1336)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1337)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1338)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1339)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1340)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1341)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1342)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1343)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1344)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1345)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1346)
    - 1956 Jan-Sep (Box 129, Folder 1347)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1348)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1349)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1350)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1351)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1352)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1353)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1354)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1355)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1356)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1357)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1358)
    - 1956 Oct-1957 May (Box 130, Folder 1359)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1360)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1361)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1362)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1363)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1364)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1365)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1366)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1367)
    - 1957 Jun-Dec (Box 131, Folder 1368)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1369)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1370)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1371)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1372)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1373)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1374)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1375)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1376)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1377)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1378)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1379)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1380)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1381)
    - 1958 Jan-Mar (Box 132, Folder 1382)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1383)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1384)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1385)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1386)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1387)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1388)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1389)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1390)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1391)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1392)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1393)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1394)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1395)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1396)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1397)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1398)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1399)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1400)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1401)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1402)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1403)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1404)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1405)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1406)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1407)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1408)
    - 1958 Apr-Sep (Box 133, Folder 1409)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1410)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1411)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1412)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1413)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1414)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1415)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1416)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1417)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1418)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1419)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1420)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1421)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1422)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1423)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1424)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1425)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1426)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1427)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1428)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1429)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1430)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1431)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1432)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1433)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1434)
    - 1958 Sep-Oct (Box 134, Folder 1435)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1436)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1437)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1438)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1439)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1440)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1441)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1442)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1443)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1444)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1445)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1446)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1447)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1448)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1449)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1450)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1451)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1452)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1453)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1454)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1455)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1456)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1457)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1458)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1459)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1460)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1461)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1462)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1463)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1464)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1465)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1466)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1467)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1468)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1469)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1470)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1471)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1472)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1473)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1474)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1475)
    - 1958 Oct-1959 Dec (Box 135, Folder 1476)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1477)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1478)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1479)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1480)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1481)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1482)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1483)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1484)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1485)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1486)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1487)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1488)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1489)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1490)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1491)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1492)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1493)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1494)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1495)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1496)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1497)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1498)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1499)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1500)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1501)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1502)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1503)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1504)
    - 1960 Apr-1965 Mar (Box 136, Folder 1505)
  - Printed Speeches, 1960 (Box 136, Folder 1506)
- Standard Oil of California, 1945-1958 (Box 136, Folder 1507)
  Correspondence with Harry D. Collier and other Standard Oil of California officials re: offers of assistance with various NAR projects and invitations to luncheons. NAR accepted Collier's offer of a car and chauffeur during the United Nations conference in San Francisco, 1945.
- Standard Oil of New Jersey
  - Analysis, 1952 (Box 136, Folder 1508)
    Analysis of desirability of investing in the oil industry.
  - Correspondence, 1941-1946 (Box 136, Folder 1509)
    Re: Standard Oil renting office space in Caracas, Venezuela, from pro-Nazi; Standard Oil employees in Venezuela suspected of being Nazi sympathizers; post-war public relations surveys. Record of proceedings of the Senate Special Committee to Investigate the National Defense Program, 4/3/42, includes mention of NAR and the "black list."
  - Seaview Conference, 1940 (Box 137, Folder 1510)
    Agenda.
  - Seaview Conference, 1940 (Box 137, Folder 1511)
  - Kennalley, J. J., Case of, 1946-1958 (Box 137, Folder 1512)
    Crank letters from a disgruntled Standard Oil employee.
  - Printed Material and Clippings, 1948-1960 (Box 137, Folder 1513)
- Statements by NAR, 1941-1950 (Box 137, Folder 1514)
  Primarily drafts of NAR's public statements as Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.
- Tate Gallery, 1960-1964 (Box 137, Folder 1515)
  NAR made an honorary trustee of the American Friends of the Tate Gallery, London, 1960.
- Temporary Commission on the Fiscal Affairs of State Government (New York), 1954 (Box 137, Folder 1516)
- Temporary State Commission on the Constitutional Convention, 1956-1958
  NAR was chairman of this New York state commission which is required to convene every twenty years to determine if the state constitution should be revised. This was his first significant exposure to New York state governmental and political issues.
  - Chronological File, 1956-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1517)
  - Commission Directors, Candidates, 1956 (Box 138, Folder 1518)
    Reports on possible director and assistant director of Commission. NAR's first notice of William J. Ronan.
  - Commission Membership, Biographies, 1956-1957 (Box 138, Folder 1519)
  - Consultants for Staff Projects, 1957 (Box 138, Folder 1520)
    Lists, assignments, cost of studies.
  - General Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1521)
    Re: organization of Commission; plans; meetings; staff; progress report; defeat at polls; Gov. Harriman's veto of proposed extension; reorganization; NAR's loans to staff until appropriation was extended (no record if NAR was compensated by the state).
  - General Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1522)
  - General Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1523)
  - Letters of Congratulation, 1956 (Box 138, Folder 1524)
    Letters sent to NAR upon appointment to Commission.
  - Goeller, Vera, 1956-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1525)
    Memos to NAR re: details of daily operation; changes; plans; programs.
  - Moore, Frank C., 1957-1958 (Box 138, Folder 1526)
    Memos to NAR re: objectives and methods of Commission.
  - Memoranda, Confidential, 1956-1957 (Box 138, Folder 1527)
    Francis A. Jamieson's memos to NAR re: political aspects of Commission work.
  - Minutes (Drafts) and Memoranda, 1956-1958 (Box 139, Folder 1528)
    Memos re: policy, style and content of minutes.
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1529)
  - Publicity - Clippings, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1530)
  - Publicity - Memorandum, 1956-1958 (Box 139, Folder 1531)
  - Publicity - Press Releases, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1532)
  - Publicity - Frank Jamieson's File, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1533)
    Memos re: NAR speeches; political issues; arranging meetings; John E. Lockwood memo on governmental issues. Press releases, clippings.
  - Publicity - Frank Jamieson's File, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1534)
  - Publicity - Frank Jamieson's File, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1535)
  - Publicity - Frank Jamieson's File, 1956-1957 (Box 139, Folder 1536)
  - Publicity - Reference Material - General, 1957 (Box 139, Folder 1537)
    Memos re: procedures for studies and hearings background; the "why" of a convention. Printed material. 1821 edition of the minutes of the 1801 New York state constitutional convention.
  - Publicity - Reference Material - General, 1821, 1957 (Box 140, Folder 1538)
  - Publicity - Reference Material - Studies, 1956-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1539)
    Reports on staff projects 1-9. Inter-law school committee report on constitutional simplification.
  - Publicity - Reference Material - Studies, 1956-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1540)
  - Publicity - Reference Material - Studies, 1956-1967 (Box 140, Folder 1541)
  - Public Hearings - Albany, 1957 (Box 140, Folder 1542)
    NAR notes, lists of issues and participants, papers by some participants.
  - Public Hearings - Buffalo, 1957 (Box 140, Folder 1543)
  - Public Hearings - New York, 1957 (Box 141, Folder 1544)
  - Public Hearings - New York, 1957 (Box 141, Folder 1545)
  - Public Hearings - New York, 1957 (Box 141, Folder 1546)
  - Reports - First Interim Report, 1957 (Box 141, Folder 1547)
  - Reports - Second Interim Report, 1957 (Box 142, Folder 1548)
  - Reports - "Staff Report on the Problem of Simplification of the Constitution", 1958 (Box 142, Folder 1549)
  - Reports - "Staff Report on the Problem of Simplification of the Constitution", 1958 (Box 142, Folder 1550)
  - Reports - "Staff Report on the Problem of Simplification of the Constitution", 1958 (Box 142, Folder 1551)
  - Speeches by NAR, 1957 (Box 142, Folder 1552)
    Arrangements for speeches, copies of speeches.
  - Vouchers, 1957 (Box 142, Folder 1553)
    Vouchers sent to NAR to cover his state expenses.
- Thirty Rockefeller Plaza Associates & Co., 1959-1960, 1963-1964 (Box 142, Folder 1554)
  An investment partnerships. Memos re: investment possibilities; notices of meetings. Reports.
- Trips, 1930-1977
  - Wedding Trip, 1930-1931 (Box 142, Folder 1555)
    Around the world honeymoon trip for NAR and Mary Todhunter Clark. Itineraries, expenses, accounts, letters of thanks from NAR to some dignitaries. Correspondence re: reservations; tickets; shipment of purchases home. Short telegrams from NAR to John Davison Rockefeller, Jr., informing him of their whereabouts and movements.
  - Mexico City, 1933 (Box 143, Folder 1556)
    By boat, visited Cuba, purchases, Mr. and Mrs. Paine.
  - Western Trip, 1934 (Box 143, Folder 1557)
    With W. W. Aldrich, Chase Bank tour, Texas, California and Washington.
  - Europe, 1935 (Box 143, Folder 1558)
    Chase Bank work in London and Paris, met w/Luval & Petain.
  - Europe, 1935 (Box 143, Folder 1559)
  - Europe, 1935 (Box 143, Folder 1560)
    Auto accident, 1935-1936.
  - Texas, 1936 (Box 143, Folder 1561)
    Armstrong Ranch hunting, Texas friendships.
  - Sun Valley, Idaho, 1936-1938, 1939-1941 (Box 143, Folder 1562)
    W. A. Harriman - Skiing Vacations.
  - South America, 1937 (Box 143, Folder 1563)
    Contacts, expenses, purchases, Peruvian mummies.
  - South America - Expenses, 1937 (Box 143, Folder 1564)
  - South America - Expenses and Itineraries, 1937 (Box 144, Folder 1565)
    Guest Lists
  - South America - Correspondence on mummies, 1937-1941 (Box 144, Folder 1566)
  - South America - Purchases, 1937 (Box 144, Folder 1567)
  - Texas, 1937 (Box 144, Folder 1568)
    King Ranch, NAR ill.
  - Arizona, 1938 (Box 144, Folder 1568A)
    Health reasons, w/W. K. Harrison.
  - Ohio and Oklahoma, 1938 (Box 144, Folder 1569)
    John Davison Rockefeller 3rd visits Hanna Coal Company mine in Willow Grove, Ohio.
  - Mexico, 1939-1940 (Box 144, Folder 1570)
    Visit to Cardenas, discuss expropriation of oil industry in Mexico.
  - Venezuela, 1939 (Box 144, Folder 1571)
    NAR memo on conditions in Venezuela.
  - Venezuela, 1939 (Box 144, Folder 1572)
  - Texas, 1939-1940 (Box 144, Folder 1573)
    Mr. and Mrs. NAR hunting, King Ranch. Armstrong & King Ranches.
  - South America, 1940 (Box 145, Folder 1574)
    Venezuela, plans for Fomento, comments on Venezuela.
  - Alaska, Yukon, 1941 (Box 145, Folder 1575)
    Hunting trip diaries.
  - South America, 1942 (Box 145, Folder 1576)
    Coordinator trip, itinerary, one purchase.
  - Haiti, Costa Rica, Venezuela, 1944 (Box 145, Folder 1577)
    Coordinator trips.
  - Brazil, 1946 (Box 145, Folder 1578)
    American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) Affairs. Planning program, meeting Brazilians.
  - South America, Mexico, 1946 (Box 145, Folder 1579)
    Personal introductions, Mexico and Brazil.
  - Venezuela, 1947 (Box 145, Folder 1580)
    International Basic Economy Corporation business with Rodman.
  - Venezuela, February 1948 (Box 145, Folder 1581)
    International Basic Economy Corporation presidential inauguration.
  - Central America, 1948 (Box 145, Folder 1582)
    Rodman ill. U.F.C. Farms.
  - Venezuela, April-May 1948 (Box 145, Folder 1583)
    International Basic Economy Corporation.
  - Mexico, 1948 (Box 145, Folder 1584)
    Family trip.
  - Venezuela, July 1948 (Box 145, Folder 1585)
    American International Association for social and Economic Development (AIA) trip with John Davison Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Brazil, 1948 (Box 146, Folder 1586)
    American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) trip with David Rockefeller.
  - Venezuela, October 1948 (Box 146, Folder 1587)
    International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) trip.
  - California, December 1948 (Box 146, Folder 1588)
    National Conference of Christians and Jews tour itinerary.
  - Italy, April 1949 (Box 146, Folder 1589)
    List of what to see.
  - Venezuela, June 1949 (Box 146, Folder 1590)
    International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) speech.
  - Europe, June-July 1949 (Box 146, Folder 1591)
  - Jamaica, February 1950 (Box 146, Folder 1592)
    Vacation with W. K. Harrison.
  - Canada, July 1950 (Box 146, Folder 1593)
    W. L. Mackenzie King funeral.
  - Brazil, Venezuela, June-July 1950 (Box 146, Folder 1594)
    American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).
  - Washington, DC - "Dollar Gap Problem", July 24, 1950 (Box 146, Folder 1595)
    Point IV beginnings.
  - Washington, DC - "Dollar Gap Problem" - Meeting with President Truman, July 24, 1950 (Box 146, Folder 1596)
  - Brazil, 1951 (Box 146, Folder 1597)
    Vargus inauguration.
  - Venezuela, June 1951 (Box 146, Folder 1598)
  - Western Trip, June 1951 (Box 147, Folder 1599)
    "Partners in Progress" swing.
  - Venezuela, February 5-13, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1600)
    International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).
  - Venezuela - Clippings, February 5-13, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1601)
  - Spain, April-May 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1602)
    Mr. and Mrs. NAR, holiday.
  - Peru, Ecuador, June-July 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1603)
    Ann and Rodman went with NAR.
  - Brazil, November 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1604)
    Mr. and Mrs. NAR.
  - Venezuela, February 1953 (Box 147, Folder 1605)
    American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA).
  - Greece, Africa, April-May 1953 (Box 147, Folder 1606)
    Boat accident, Belgian Congo.
  - Scotland, Europe, 1953 (Box 147, Folder 1607)
    Mrs. NAR and children to France, then NAR and family in Scotland - grouse shooting.
  - Caneel Bay, Virgin Islands, February-March 1954 (Box 147, Folder 1608)
  - Venezuela, November 1954 (Box 147, Folder 1609)
  - Germany, June 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1610)
    To Bonn on official U.S. mission.
  - France, July 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1611)
  - Venezuela, August 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1612)
  - England, Germany, November 1955 (Box 147, Folder 1613)
    Frankfurt, Berlin, London, Bonn, Rodman's baby.
  - Venezuela, January 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1614)
    Itinerary.
  - Cleveland, Ohio, February 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1615)
    V.D. Anderson Company.
  - Caneel Bay, Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, February 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1616)
  - Venezuela, Brazil, Ecuador, March-April 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617)
    With Michael, Steven and David.
  - Africa - General, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617.1)
    Sightseeing with family.
    Restricted material from Folder 1617a
  - Africa - General - Itinerary, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617.2)
    Restricted material from Folder 1617B
  - Africa - General - Letters of Appreciation, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617.3)
    Restricted material from Folder 1617C
  - Africa - General - Purchases, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617.4)
    Restricted material from Folder 1617E
  - Africa - General, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617A)
  - Trips - Africa - General - Itinerary, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617B)
  - Africa - General - Letters of Appreciation, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617C)
  - Africa - General - Medical Guidelines for Travel, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617)
  - Africa - General - Purchases, July 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1617E)
  - San Francisco, CA, August 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1618)
    Republican Convention.
  - Panama, El Salvador, September-October 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1619)
    Inauguration of E. de La Guardia.
  - Venezuela, November-December 1956 (Box 148, Folder 1620)
    Farms and International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).
  - Venezuela, January-February 1957 (Box 148, Folder 1621)
  - Caneel Bay, Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico, February 1957 (Box 148, Folder 1622)
    Mr. and Mrs. NAR and Louise Boyer.